Guide to the Robert Alan Dahl Papers
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
Robert Alan Dahl papers
1910-1959
1957-1959
MS 1658
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
3
(3 boxes)
The papers consist of interview notes, transcripts, and survey responses used in Robert A. Dahl's book Who Governs?, and background research material about New Haven.
Dahl, Robert A., 1915-2014
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Gift of Robert A. Dahl, 1994.
Conditions Governing Access
Interview notes, transcripts, and survey responses are closed until January 1, 2020.
Biographical / Historical
Robert Alan Dahl was born in Inwood, Iowa on December 17, 1915. He received an A.B. degree from the University of Washington in 1936, and his Ph.D. from Yale University in 1940. Dahl joined the faculty of Yale's political science department in 1946. He is the author of several books and has received numerous professional awards. Dahl died in Hamden, Connecticut, on February 5, 2014.
Scope and Contents
The papers consist of interview notes, transcripts, and survey responses used in Robert A. Dahl's book Who Governs?, and background research material about New Haven.
Minority college students -- United States; Minorities -- Education -- United States; New Haven (Conn.) -- Politics and government; Dahl, Robert A., 1915-2014; Yale University -- Students
- Inventory
  - Who Governs? [background information], 1957, undated (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - New Haven
    - Background data, 1910-1958 (Box 1, Folder 2 - 4)
    - Charter election survey, 1958 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Education, 1957-1958 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Elections and officials [compiled data from various sources going back to 1800] (Box 1, Folder 7 - 8)
    - Political Parties, 1958, undated (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - Social and economic notables, undated (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - Redevelopment, 1957, undated (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - Community leadership study, 1958 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Confidential report to Mayor Lee, 1959 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Survey #1
    - Methodology, 1959 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Survey #2, 1959
    - Background (Box 1, Folder 15 - 19)
    - Analysis [by Dan Lewis] (Box 1, Folder 20)
    - Figures: correlations, ethnicity, race, etc. (Box 1, Folder 21)
    - Special tablulations (Box 1, Folder 22 - 23)
  - Interview notes, translations, survey responses, 1959 (Box 2–3)
    Conditions Governing Access
    These records are closed until January 1, 2020.